<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://arcadio-buendia.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://arcadio-buendia.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2023-07-23T14:30:18+00:00</updated><id>https://arcadio-buendia.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jahr</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">The last day of M.Sc.</title><link href="https://arcadio-buendia.github.io/blog/2023/MSC/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The last day of M.Sc."/><published>2023-07-18T13:16:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-18T13:16:00+00:00</updated><id>https://arcadio-buendia.github.io/blog/2023/MSC</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arcadio-buendia.github.io/blog/2023/MSC/"><![CDATA[<p>I woke up at 5am in the morning and then dozed on and off for another two hours. When wakefulness came at about 7, I was desperately late to do any useful revision. So I took a look at my notes, the ppt slides and a few PDFs for 2 hours before I had to leave my room. The exam room was already filled except the two of us, and the examiner asked us to sit quickly. I was feeling a certain way. It was not fear or anxiety that one feels before an exam but a sort of tiredness. I didn’t want to do the exam. As I stared at the paper, I realized how easy it was. As I thought about the answer, my brain wandered. A little supernova burst up with pressure, the metal factory was in full pace just a moment ago, and now it has exploded. Its dying glory can be seen from thousands of light years. But no, I wasn’t supposed to go there. I was supposed to write down the affine connections given a metric. Einstein had used them in his general theory of relativity, and cosmologist use them today to find the behavior of bodies close to that supernovae. I was not interested. But today was not about my interest. It was about a sheet of paper. A sheet of paper that could define my future. The future that would be better if I had studied the subject. Now it lies miserably in the hands and mood of the examiner. With this, I have completed the requirements of a Master’s Degree in Physics.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I woke up at 5am in the morning and then dozed on and off for another two hours. When wakefulness came at about 7, I was desperately late to do any useful revision. So I took a look at my notes, the ppt slides and a few PDFs for 2 hours before I had to leave my room. The exam room was already filled except the two of us, and the examiner asked us to sit quickly. I was feeling a certain way. It was not fear or anxiety that one feels before an exam but a sort of tiredness. I didn’t want to do the exam. As I stared at the paper, I realized how easy it was. As I thought about the answer, my brain wandered. A little supernova burst up with pressure, the metal factory was in full pace just a moment ago, and now it has exploded. Its dying glory can be seen from thousands of light years. But no, I wasn’t supposed to go there. I was supposed to write down the affine connections given a metric. Einstein had used them in his general theory of relativity, and cosmologist use them today to find the behavior of bodies close to that supernovae. I was not interested. But today was not about my interest. It was about a sheet of paper. A sheet of paper that could define my future. The future that would be better if I had studied the subject. Now it lies miserably in the hands and mood of the examiner. With this, I have completed the requirements of a Master’s Degree in Physics.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cpsymmetry</title><link href="https://arcadio-buendia.github.io/blog/2020/cpsymmetry/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cpsymmetry"/><published>2020-12-04T12:13:15+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-04T12:13:15+00:00</updated><id>https://arcadio-buendia.github.io/blog/2020/cpsymmetry</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arcadio-buendia.github.io/blog/2020/cpsymmetry/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://scinats.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cosmos-92368_1280.jpg" alt="mirror like example of cp symmetry"/>{.attachment-post-thumbnail .size-post-thumbnail .wp-post-image width=”1280” height=”973” loading=”lazy” srcset=”https://i0.wp.com/scinats.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cosmos-92368_1280.jpg?w=1280&amp;ssl=1 1280w, https://i0.wp.com/scinats.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cosmos-92368_1280.jpg?resize=300%2C228&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/scinats.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cosmos-92368_1280.jpg?resize=1024%2C778&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/scinats.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cosmos-92368_1280.jpg?resize=768%2C584&amp;ssl=1 768w” sizes=”(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px”}</p> <p><em>CP Symmetry ( Charge Parity and Symmetry Parity) problem is one of the greatest mysteries of physics. The <a href="https://www.symmetrymagazine.org/article/july-2015/standard-model">standard model of physics</a>{.rank-math-link aria-label=”standard model of physics (opens in a new tab)” rel=”noreferrer noopener” target=”_blank”} predicts that matter and <a href="https://scinats.com/index.php/2020/09/19/about-antimatter/">anti-matter</a>{.rank-math-link aria-label=”anti-matter (opens in a new tab)” rel=”noreferrer noopener” target=”_blank”} should have annihilated each other until nothing remained. Yet the universe exists in all it’s grandeur as is evident with the first breath you take.</em></p> <p>Humans judge beauty by symmetry. Studies show that we judge a person of symmetric face to be better looking than one with less symmetry. Interestingly, the case of CP symmetry is just this human bias entering the scientific world. This is not the first time that such a bias has been made in science. “Einstein’s greatest blunder” is another case of the same bias. Here we look at how chasing a perfection in the universe went wrong and the eventual realization that the universe is imperfect.</p> <p>Interestingly, annihilation happens when a particle hits an antiparticle or matter vs antimatter war. If you are new to our blog, you <a href="https://scinats.com/author/prabin/">can read other articles from here to grasp the concepts used</a>{.rank-math-link} in easy language.</p> <p>However, this requires the particles and anti-particles to be exact opposites in charge, space (parity), and time. So that when they collide nothing remains but energy. However, in our universe, there is the presence of <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/why-is-there-more-matter-than-antimatter/">more matter than anti-matter.</a>{.rank-math-link target=”_blank” rel=”noopener”}</p> <blockquote> <p>So, is that an error 404?</p> </blockquote> <p>It gives rise to one of the biggest problem of physics which is still not solved. So, why are you waiting, go and try to solve it? The next Nobel Prize in physics can be all yours. The question is “In Observable Universe, why there is the presence of more matter than anti-matter?”</p> <h2 id="what-exactly-is-cp-symmetry">What exactly is CP Symmetry?</h2>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Design Inefficiency]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mismatch</title><link href="https://arcadio-buendia.github.io/blog/2015/mismatch/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mismatch"/><published>2015-05-15T21:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-05-15T21:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://arcadio-buendia.github.io/blog/2015/mismatch</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arcadio-buendia.github.io/blog/2015/mismatch/"><![CDATA[<p>Humans have developed for more than <em>50,000</em> years in an ancient resource-lacking environment. Putting a body designed in that environment into the one we have today is a <em>sacrilege</em> of it’s design.</p> <p>The cravings and aversions of the human body are meant to help us survive in the wild. When we put them to navigate the modern world. It’s no wonder that we go ashtray.</p> <p>This is the reason we can keep on scrolling instagram to no concievable end or binge eat junk food while binge watching netflix lying on a sofa. While being aware that it is hurting us all the time.</p> <p>These products chips, netflix or instagram are designed to hack the biological response and reward system of the human body. While our bodies are still trying to crave things that we might need in the wild where it isn’t easily available. The products that we see in front of us give us exactly that in optimized amounts to hit our bliss point.</p> <h2 id="salary">Salary</h2> <p>The response-reward system that would be the most important tool to help us differentiate what to do and what not to is skewed hacked and made use of by our current enviconrments. Even our society is based off of that.</p> <p>Just think of your salary. We get a little amount every month. Most of us have the feeling of having that short chilll of happiness even after decades of getting it. This is one way in which the current societal structure takes advantage of our design. Infact, the societal structure evolved to leverage on humans more than humans could leverage societal structure.</p> <p>Therefore, those who successfully navigate the social structure are few and they gain all of it while the rest of trapped in the tricks of our bodies with ancient designs are left out to survive.</p> <h2 id="instagram">Instagram</h2> <p>You know that endlessly scrolling instagram is bad for we but we do it anyway. It has hacked into so many of your biological systems. The craving to make social connections that would help us in the wild as people wihtout a society are to die first. We needed friend we could hunt with and trust them to share food. We also needed people to keep we from starving when we are sick and unable. We needed to have strong social connection made through chatting, gossiping, knowing what others are up to and so on. The current model of social media gives us all that wihtout the strong social connection and the great advantages that cam e in the real world. We already live in the virutal world that please our reward-response system.</p> <p>We also needed mates to reproduce. This is perhaps the most important thing(link back to medium article saying one predetermined goal of the human life is reproduction) for any organism “reproduction”. We did this by meeting people usually from our own social group, bonding with the healthier ones and then mating.</p> <p>So we are naturally inclined to like things like symmetry in body structure, big hips for women, tall-mascular men. Social media provides us a plethora of such specimen and we get hooked up to tit. If that wasns’t enough, surgeries can be performed to look attractive when attractive is simply a tool to find a good reproductive partner. IT has been hacked to do everything but that.</p> <h2 id="chips">Chips</h2> <p>Sweet and oily things are rich in energy. It is the fuel that the body needs to keep on going. Thus the reward-response mechanicsm for sweet and oily things is quite strong. These were scarce in the environemnt that our body evolved in and thus more was always good. Our cravings are therefore inclined to grab a lot of them when we can. This is simply not true in the current environment where more poeple die from <em>obesity each year than starvation</em>. Our mind is however still ancient, and the rewards in terms of feeling good are still quite high for oily and sweet food. Making us not only binge on them but also makin git a habit to do so. But in today’s world where <em>more people die of obesity each year than from starvation</em> it is a not true.</p> <h2 id="cheap-dopamine">Cheap Dopamine</h2> <p>What all of this means is that the dopamine that was a reward for something well done. The dopamine that would incite a rewards-response cycle to keep us from dying has been hacked in bizzare ways. The cheap dopamine environment of the modern world leads us to have a sedantary life full of unhealthy habits that push us into depression and death. *Make the depression point clearer. Maybe add that to the instagarm place. *Often these habits have a loop, we like watching TV and while watching Tv to have chips. These are both high dopamine activities and now whenever we watch TV we have an urge to have chips *When we are sad we scroll through IG which makes we more depressed as we compare, which makes we watch more of IG</p> <h2 id="the-aversion-pathways">The aversion pathways</h2> <ul> <li>Bitter things are usually poisonous</li> <li>Physical work is tiresome and wastes energy that might be needed later. Therefore it is a good idea to save energy and not do any physical work unless we have to.</li> <li>Mental work: We don’t want to be eaten away by a lion while we are seriously trying to find the formula for the height of a right angle triangle.</li> </ul> <p><img src="contraception.md" alt=""/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Design Inefficiency]]></summary></entry></feed>